Two rounds of diving to come and this is how it stands as we head into the final stages of this competition.
Tonya Couch leads still for Great Britain with a really good score but it's this second page where all the action is because the top 12 of 20 go through to the final in this women's 10 meter platform and at the moment it's Green Agadama of Lithuania that has dived herself into a qualification zone.
Germany's Christina Ahsen.
Great start, then a little wobble, then a brilliant comeback.
So the 16-year-old looking good for a place in the final.
Forward three and a half then for round four.
That's a lot of rotation in the pike position and knew it, she had to leave this dive spinning a bit longer than she wanted and ran out of room.
Yeah, now classic mistake, jumps forward, but here she pulls in and suddenly it picks up the rotation and she was surprised by it and came out too late.
49.50.
If you've ever sat in one of those rotating office chairs, put your arms and legs out and rotated, you'll go around quite slowly.
And while you're doing that, then pull your arms and legs in fast and watch your increased rotation.
And that's basically the physics that are working here.
By the way, don't hurt yourself while you're doing it.
Pichikova needs a recovery dive here.
Arm stand forward, two somersaults, single twist.
Lovely arm stand.
Oh, that's a classy dive from start to finish.
Yeah, I like the start there.
Hips forward, flick off, bend the twist, and then the line up.
She bends her arms, that's the right way to go, just a little bit low though, with the head going past the board, but it's the entry that's important.
And into the 60s, Pechikova should climb a couple of places with that one.
Tianga Vila-Kromos then.
Talked about this twister for her.
during the course of the competition.
Is this the dive that is going to be a problem because she has a lot of heavy black tape around her neck?
This will put the head under pressure.
Oh, it's kept the head in place.
Beautifully done.
Yeah, no wobble at all.
Ah, it's a brilliant twist.
That's the way to do it.
A slight over-twist going through the water.
I think because the dive is so pretty, they're not going to mark too many points off.
Might just keep it under 60.
57-40.
Villa-Cormos, I think she's going to be OK with that score.
I think they should maintain her qualification position with one round to go.
No problem so far, though, in terms of qualification for Great Britain's Tonya Couch.
First position for the last couple of rounds, back two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists in the pike position then for Tonya in round four at 3.2.
will most definitely be a medal contender come this evening because she is going to be in the final.
Yeah, very strong take off.
Just a little loose with the legs going through the water.
Good twist.
Reasonably strong pull in on the bike.
Not fully locked out on the end.
It doesn't matter though.
The crowd are loving this.
All the school children in for this afternoon's session, enjoying the fact that Couch keeps getting the scores.
They keep putting number one beside her name, and that's what the fans are enjoying.
Now, Kristina Sieszka doesn't look like she's enjoyed her competition, I'm afraid.
The young Belarus diver back three and a half somersaults in the tuck position.
This is a big dive.
This is joint most difficult dive in the competition.
And the way she's been diving, Chris, well, you don't hold out much hope, really.
Yeah, Georgia Ward did the back three and a half and went short on the entry.
Oh, well, she just about got there.
Well done.
Yeah, and that was a real struggle.
The head's in the wrong position, it's spinning slow, and they're very untidy as she kicks out.
And the huge twist going through the water.
44.55.
I think the fact that she's safely down, more important.
But Sheska won't be heading to the final.
Sophia Reisinger, if she wants to go,
to a European Championship final here in London.
Then she has to hit this dive and she has to hit her final round dive as well, both at 2.8.
Reverse two and a half.
She's 35 points out of 12th place.
No, and that is probably it, I'm afraid, for Sophia for today.
That's a poor dive.
She jumps forward, she feels slow in the spin so she's overcompensated by staying in the tuck longer.
Also she has a problem spotting on this dive, she doesn't see the water before kicking out.
Fairly passive response at the moment but she will be very disappointed.
Expected to see Sofia in the final but not happening I'm afraid for the 26-year-old Hungarian.
Arm stand back to somersaults with one and a half twists then for Laura Marrano of France.
She finishes with two twisting dives both at 3.2 and she is on her way at the moment to the final.
Good position.
Yeah, good dive from Marinosa.
That'll be fine.
Yeah, she gets to jump off the platform.
Yeah, good jump.
Just a little anxiety and scrappy with the feet, though.
They're the feet apart, and then they come apart again here before she lines up.
She loses about five or six points for that.
57.60, though, is going to be absolutely fine for Laura.
France still going along well with both divers.
16th place for Ellen Eck.
If she wanted a place in the top 12 today she knew that every single dive had to be as good as she could make it.
She's been just back off her best so these last two rounds are vital.
She might need another diver to miss as well if she's going to qualify.
She's 33 points out of top 12.
So close.
She'll be disappointed with the entry because it was all going well.
Just everything's too slow though.
Finished about three and a half metres off the water.
Need to finish a lot higher than that.
Good pike position.
The hands just get caught in front of the ears and so the water splashed off the top of their head.
Just 52.20 then for Ellen.
Qualification remains in doubt.
That's a nice look.
That's been around about the ninth position for the whole of the competition, the 20-year-old Ukraine diver, so he's looking at a place in the final.
Back two and a half somersaults in the pike position then at 2.9, but there's no room for error here for Hanna.
Yeah, it's a good dive under pressure.
Wasn't sure she was going to make that with that leave of the platform.
Yeah, when she jumped, she didn't extend her legs.
Her legs are bent.
But the pike here on the second part of the dive was good.
And then she disappears.
And the feet, a lot better as well.
Nicely pointed.
So judges like that, 56.55.
And that should protect Krasnoshlyk's place at the moment.
Georgia Ward had one little blip in her program.
Ever popular with the crowd, the British divers, but she's recovered nicely from her blip.
Round four then, forward three and a half.
Oh, and that one's whipped over at the end as well.
And we'll see what the judges do with this.
Oh, what a takeoff.
It was brilliant.
She finishes so high.
There's the double coming around.
One more.
I don't think she was used to such a great takeoff.
That was superb.
But unfortunately, entry's so important.
46.50.
Georgia Ward is going to have to find her best in the last round if she wants to qualify for this evening's final.
That'd be such a shame if she missed out because she is clearly a talent and could definitely put pressure on for the medals.
15th position at the moment for Celine Van Doorn, had done some great work to get into the top 12, rose as high as 11 and then a miss in the last round.
So this arm stand back to somersaults with one and a half twists has got to be good.
Little too quick out of that one and a little too splashy going through the water.
I'm not sure this will improve her situation.
Very lucky on the end here.
Gets the push but late into the twist.
Just gets the hands to the water but not fully locked out.
Oh, they've liked it.
She'll take that any day of the week.
62.40.
She was expecting to turn around and see a mid-50 score there.
But Salim Van Doorn is still in business.
Anvilder Tuiksen in last place at the moment.
Some personal goals will have been set for today's performance.
It'll be all about the score.
Two dives left then to prove herself.
Inward two and a half.
And one of her better dives today.
Yeah, this will be the highest scoring dive.
She hasn't got above 13 on the first four dives, three dives.
Pulling in hard, but then breaking position, feet going flat before lining up.
Ooh.
42 marks.
42.
There we go.
So took some of the rather solemn look back to the scoreboard as we go back
to the top of our leaderboard with Maria Cujo.
Back two and a half somersaults in the pike position then for the German.
A little bit like Bakke today, she's kind of slid under the radar.
Just gone about her business and has been solid.
And okay, not her best, but that's still heading towards qualification.
Yeah, it's been very consistent.
First dive sixth place, then in second, then third.
This will keep her up in the top five or six.
Yeah, no problems.
56.55.
Quick check with the coach about their view on that particular dive, but that's fine.
Liliya Prokopchuk.
With the big names, you're never far away from a dive that just establishes exactly where they are in the pecking order.
And in the last round, Prokopchuk
sent out a little message to the rest of the field.
If you want gold, it's me you've got to beat.
Great diving to recover.
Arm stand back, three somersaults in the tuck position at 3.3.
Big dive.
And a big score coming, a really big score coming.
I think she's about 75, 76 points behind Tonya Couch.
And this 3-3 is going to definitely be in the 70s.
Strong kick out, great reach back.
Oh, look at that, 75-90.
And Prokopchuk reclaims the lead from Tonya Couch.
At the top of the leaderboard there's just 0.15 in it between Prokopchuk and Couch and the likes of Cuiar, Marino and Batki all through.
But it's this part of the leaderboard that we're interested in.
Angadama hangs on to 12th position.
Georgia Ward has improved her placing to 13th.
for Great Britain, but this final round of diving is going to be very tense indeed.
Horrendously difficult competition to qualify through to the final.
20 divers, 12 places available off the women's 10 metre platform for this evening's final.
Naomi Backke next onto the board should be going there for Italy without any dramas, but there's a lot of drama around position 12 at the moment.
Italy then for a place in the final.
And the 28-year-old, she won't be pleased with that dive, but she'll be appearing tonight to compete for medals.
Yeah, jumps away from the platform, cuts off the height, and another diver finishing low to the water.
But she was in fifth, and she will dive better in the final.
Former European champion back in 2011.
Just licking a little bit off at the moment.
284, though.
That's a comfortable qualification.
And she and Mam Ibole
She'll be going away to have a chat about how they put that dive list together for this evening's final.
Back to the other end of the leaderboard and Isabelle Svantesen of Sweden.
This is about signing off in style and coming away with a positive dive.
She won't be going to the final.
But she has benefited from the experience and again another diver going a long, long way down the pool and away from the platform.
Yeah, just it's the technique.
If you haven't got the right timing on the jump, the momentum of the run down the board just drags you forward.
Highest score so far is 46.
There we go.
An improvement and a positive.
47.85, but still under the 200 mark across five rounds of diving.
Christina Bassen shouldn't be a problem for her.
Sixth position at the moment.
finishes with this back twister at 3.2.
And on occasion, the German has looked really good.
And she will be trying to dive like that all the way through the final this evening.
Yeah, it's a good strong finish.
Beautiful twist.
And she knows the end sheet again.
She will be pleased with this.
She finished 15th last year, had a terrible competition, and didn't make the final.
First diver over 300 is Kristina Vassin.
Another 70 score for her.
And the smile confirms a place in the final.
So Germany should qualify two through.
Russia still in doubt as to whether they can qualify both their divers.
Is there hope now?
Seventh position after four rounds.
Final dive back two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists.
And that will be Ekaterina through to the final again.
Not her best by any means, but safe enough.
same thing bends the knees and the hips go back so it's jumping backwards into the twister rather than up and it makes it hard to pull into the pike after one and a half twists.
286.35.
She's safe.
Yeah slightly better than back kick but still not into the 300s.
Pressure dive then for Giangui Villacormos will have seen her great friend
Sophia Reisinger missed her last round, so no, she's Hungary's only chance.
Well, again, toes mighty tight to the end, and she's gone right over on the finish, and she might have blown it with this dive.
Yeah, I don't think she's going to make 270.
She was in 10th place, good 3.5 at this point, but then out way too late.
Oh dear, 2.5310 and it looks like both Hungarians are going to miss out this evening.
Oh, that's a real shame.
Britain though, still with a chance of qualifying too.
Couch has been in top spot for most of this competition, just been surpassed by Prokopciuk in the last round, but Couch to finish strongly
And to go through to the final as one of the gold medal favorites.
That's the entry of the day.
That's the best reverse two and a half we've seen in the competition.
Jump strong, spots the water, kicks tight, reaches back and she squeezes her ears and all the splash goes down with her.
What a message to send out.
Another 70 score for Couch and 345-20.
That's a brilliant performance.
Christina Szczeska for Belarus.
Has been a little nervy up there, hasn't found her best form but has still managed to turn in a reasonable score but from 17th is outside the qualification zone.
but will take a positive finish away from this prelim.
Legs a little bit messy at the top, but the entry was fine.
Yeah, she'll now be just working on adding an extra twist to that half twist.
Good pike position.
Didn't grab her hands correctly, she grabbed her wrist rather than the back of her hand.
2.28.0, so confirmation that Sheshka will not be going through to the final, but she says cheerio with a smile.
Nice final dive from her.
Tough position for Sophia Reisinger to be in the 26 year old, one of the most experienced divers at this prelim competition but knows that this dive is a dive to nothing because she won't be going through to the final this evening.
Back one and a half somersaults then with two and a half twists to finish for Sophia.
Oh, that's an incredibly frustrating competition and finish for her.
She'll just have to look back on the bronze from the synchro competition here and enjoy that.
And she'll be disappointed with the entry because the dive itself was very good, but she lifted the chest up on the entry and dropped a little short.
2-0-7, 8-0, and that is way off Reisinger's ability.
Her best score is 3-10, so 100 points less than she's capable of doing.
Not a great day at the office for either of the Hungarian divers.
Laura Maranel then at 22 years of age just coming into that peak zone for platform divers.
Got the experience, got the skills, certainly got the degree of difficulty on the dive list.
and proved it last year with that silver medal.
And in with Prokopciuk and Couch and Batki and Kurczuk, she will go through as one of the favourites for a medal.
OK, a little flutter with the feet and a horrible entry means a miss in the final round.
But it'll be good enough for qualification.
That's so unusual.
She didn't swing her arms up fast enough, so there's no rotation here.
Tries to pull into a tight pike, but it hasn't worked.
She was lucky that she got all the way around.
Oh my goodness.
Just 40 marks.
271.50.
And now Marino is going to have to wait and see.
I thought she was safely home and dry there.
This is incredibly tight around position 12, around that bubble.
Heck, then.
Can she cause a problem?
Oh, a little bit too low to the water there as she came out the Swede.
It was a good final dive but she's too far back I'm sure to get into the top 12.
At the moment you just don't know with this competition.
Well the bubble looks like it's going to be around about that 270 mark which is the Le Colony of France, 278.5 everybody above that might just be safe but
You're never sure until the competition is finished.
2.38.20.
Elanek won't be going through.
That's one thing we can be sure of.
Hannah Krasnoshlyk in eighth position.
There are no guarantees in this prelim.
And that battle for top twelve is going to be tight.
Two seventy or around there are all in with a chance.
Can Krushin Oshluk push everybody down one position here with this dive?
Reverse two and a half somersaults then for the Ukraine diver.
Oh, very slow spin, but she's done the right thing at the end there, Chris, and managed to get it into the water.
Yeah, she slipped forward off the ball, finished very low.
I was looking at the scores.
To be safe, I was reckoning around she needs 48, 50 points.
And she's just about got that, I think.
Yeah, she has.
She's fine.
278, 1-0.
So Krzysztof Noszloch goes into the top 12.
And that will just bump everybody down a position.
That puts Julia Timoshenina now into 10th.
Colony down to ninth.
Moreno as well in eighth on 271.50 which leaves the door wide open for this young lady.
20-year-old Georgia Ward from Great Britain with a good degree of difficulty on this inward three and a half.
This for a place in the final.
Oh, it's going to be very close.
Just out of sync on that entry, but this is going to be really tight.
Maybe around 58 points will get her into the top 12.
Oh, just a little early on the out.
The judges like it.
278.15.
So she goes 0.5 ahead of Krushnozsluk.
And that looks like Georgia Ward and Tonya Couch in the final for this evening's competition for Great Britain.
Oh, the pressure passing down the line.
Celine van Doorn now for the Netherlands in 11th place.
but this is by no means a guaranteed place in the final.
Back two and a half somersaults in the pike at 2.9.
This has to be really good to make it.
Oh, good response to the pressure, but the splash might be an issue here.
She needs to get over 50.
No, about 48 points, 50 points.
I'm not sure where she get it.
It's a shame, she's caught all the water on the back of the shoulders.
Oh, I think she's done just enough.
274.25.
That puts Van Duen in at seventh place, just ahead of Van Gerama, Marino and Colonyi.
Yeah, mathematically she will go through.
She's fine.
And Vildertuxen then.
We can take a little break from the drama of qualification.
because Tucson won't be going to the final, so this is about a positive finish to the competition.
Big dive for her, the back twister, at 3.2.
Oh, and she's done it well.
Great finish.
Yeah, a little wobbly on the end.
Good twist.
The pike though, a little untidy, going from the twist now into the pike.
Legs aren't really locked out, toes could be a bit more pointed.
So just over the 200 mark for Tuchsin, but no qualification to the final.
So two divers to come to finish off this 10 meter competition.
And then we will know our top 12 to go through from the 20 this afternoon.
And both of them should qualify.
Maria Cujo first for Germany, then Liliya Prokopchuk for Ukraine.
And it's not great, I'm afraid, from Cujo.
Fortunately for her, she was way up the leaderboard ahead of this dive.
Yeah, no jump, finishes low, washes over, feet flat.
That was a poor dive.
She was in third, but she needed 95 points to go ahead of Tonya.
She was too many points back.
She's fine.
So Kujo 294.55 is through to the final and signs off with a kiss.
Last diver, defending champion Lulia Prokopchuk will bump Kolonyi out of the top 12 for France but Laura Marino is going to hang on in 12th position, assuming that Prokopchuk just gets the score out of this dive.
Slightly ponderous back twister, but what an entry.
She needs 71.30 to go ahead of Tonya Couch.
And it's a high degree of difficulty.
Good twist there.
Pulls him really well.
But because of the entry, just a little bit wobbly.
I'm not sure she hasn't got it.
No, second place.
That means Tonya Couch does win the prelims and will go through as the favorite for gold to this evening's final.
But that's going to be one heck of a shootout between her and the defending champion.
And let's not forget that whole host of names to factor in.
The likes of Kujo and Batki will be there.
Kristina Wasson going really well, both Germans in third and fourth.
Pejikova's made it through.
Georgia Ward, brilliant finish to qualify in seventh position.
So Great Britain have two competitors through.
But here's the important facts.
Timah Shenina has missed out and Kolonyi does hang on for the 12th place.
Laura Marino in 11th and France do qualify 2-3 but that is a very tight competition.
It's going to be a brilliant final.
The divers being introduced to a fantastic crowd here at the London Aquatic Centre this evening for the women's 10-metre final.
Maria Kozja for Germany just making her way out, certainly amongst the favourites.
Followed by her compatriot.
What a great performance from the 17-year-old in the prelims, Kristina Vasin, to get through in third place and to follow Kristina.
The two big guns in tonight's competition.
Lulia Prokocza looking pretty cool.
The Ukraine defending champion.
Looking to make it another win to add to the four that she already has on this apparatus.
And can Tonya Couch do it tonight?
Brilliant performance in the prelims from the British girl.
Antonia Couch comes into this final as marginal favourite, but that's going to be a very good shootout to watch between Prokopchuk and Couch.
Simon Golding and former Olympian Eurosport diving expert Chris Snowd alongside me for you.
Coverage this evening from the diving pool.
Two great events to look forward to.
The first one up should be very interesting indeed.
Women's 10m is always interesting.
But the standard was so high this morning, you had to get 270 just to make the top 12.
Normally it's 250.
And there was a blinding performance from Tonya.
Never had a medal in the individual Europeans on 10 meter before.
and she beat the reigning champion, Prokopchuk.
They both averaged 70 points and it could go even higher today.
And to put that into context in terms of the points for the gold and how that compares with the Chinese with Rio just around the corner.
Well, if you take Shen Ruilin in 2008, she averaged 89.4 a dive.
Got that world record of 447 points.
Yes, that does put it into context but tonight it's all about the European Championship and the winner of the next gold medal in the women's 10-meter platform competition as I said Tonya Couch for the home nation comes in as marginal favourite and she's got George Award for company who has a very good dive list indeed she has a degree of difficulty that could get her a medal but there's a whole host of athletes that could be on the podium by the end of this one
12 divers have qualified through from the prelim competition of 20 for this women's 10 meter platform final.
The first of two gold medals on offer in the diving pool on day five of the 2016 European Aquatics Championships.
And they go right up to the highest platform in this fabulous diving arena.
to contest gold medal number eight.
Well, Tonya Couch for Great Britain was in superb form in the prelims, but all of the divers, it has to be said, did miss a dive.
So we've always got that potential for this event to be turned on its head if someone who misses, misses with a very low score.
We hope that doesn't happen this evening on Friday the 13th.
We hope that we get a very good contest for the gold medal.
France have qualified two athletes through.
Eli Kalonjic is going to be the first diver, the 18-year-old.
She'll be followed straight away by her senior compatriot, Laura Maranot, who took silver last time out.
But for Kalonjic, this is very much a step up to the senior level.
And she's going to open with an inward two and a half somersaults at 2.8.
And that's a fine start.
Yeah, brilliant start.
She didn't hang about either.
As soon as she was on the end, she sprung off.
It's the entry that was impressive though.
Springy jump, good line up, just a tad over.
But because there's hardly any splash, fantastic pike there.
She's going to score really well.
Gets the roll on the end, just maybe one or two degrees over.
Well, let's hope this is a sign of things to come in terms of scoring.
coach by Frederic Pierre.
And you'll see the coaches interacting with the divers on a constant basis.
If you're new to the sport of diving here on Eurosport, that's a normal feature.
The divers get feedback constantly from the coaches and very much encourage it as well.
And as soon as that's happened, then they go off and start to visualize for the next
round of dives which means the camera operator has to follow them so that we can get score graphic up at some point we will have it in a moment for you I can tell you based on what we've heard in the background from the judges scores it's gonna be a good one it will be a good one she got 61 in the prelims and this was far superior any moment now
but I think this is going to be a cracking opening score for Oleg Kolonji.
Well, with an entry like that, the diver's worth at least eight, maybe even more.
He had no splash whatsoever.
Now, I still predict that it's going to be an average of 70 or more to win this contest.
So if any of the girls can get close to that throughout, then they're going to get gold, silver or bronze.
And that's not far off, is it?
67.20 from Koloknji.
Good start from the French number two.
And we turn to the French number one for the next dive.
Laura Maronok in with three and a half somersaults in the tuck position at 3.2.
She might be diving as the 11th qualifier, but she has the scoring capability and the tariff on the dives to make a big impression this evening.
And remember, prelim score goes out the window.
This is back to square one.
Marillot then for France.
Inward three and a half in the tuck position.
Oh, it's a miss.
And this is what the contest could come down to tonight, Chris.
If you do miss, it's by how much you miss.
Yeah, and that was disastrous.
She went 72 points in the prelims.
There, though, she fell out of it out too late.
Little bit close with her hair coming around on the first somersault.
There's that miss there.
Doesn't pick up the water on the triple.
You need to be able to spot the water, come out quick.
Silver medal last year.
Well, this was, as Chris said, 72 in the prelims.
This will be closer to 27.
It's certainly not going to make it into the 50s.
Remains to be seen if she can make it into the 40s.
She can.
49.60.
So Marrano gets off to a poor start and the 2015 silver medalist in this event under pressure already.
Now, what a refreshing change this young lady was earlier today.
17-year-old Genevieve Green Anjarami from Lithuania, but actually left Lithuania when she was two years of age and has done all of her diving in the USA, trains alongside World Championship Synchro finalist Kasady Kuk.
And a horrible inward two and a half to start, I'm afraid.
And you heard the crowd groan.
This has gone badly wrong.
Yeah, it's right on the start.
She slips right here.
Oh, she is so lucky that that didn't go badly, badly wrong for her.
Yeah, she slips and you just, there was nothing to push against.
She was actually lucky that her feet didn't hit on that first somersault as well.
That would have stopped her completely there.
She's smiling.
Oh, she's unbelievable.
They're tough, aren't they?
Yeah, still smiling away.
Whole competition to go, but has to accept a sub-20 mark, I'm afraid, for that opener.
So Anjan Ami, having made the final, big day for her.
That was a huge result.
Unfortunately, hasn't got the start she wanted in the final itself.
Next up from the Netherlands, Celine van Doen, 23 years of age now, starts with a back twister.
So back two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists in the pike position.
Well, you just heard in the background the announcer here in the stadium just letting everybody know that there is an input issue with the scoring pads.
We've had the odd electronic gremlin during the course of this week, Chris, but it's to be expected.
It's a very complex system.
It is and what happens though if the pads don't work and it looks like it's going to delay the competition then they go to flip cards the old system back to the good old days yes and i think that's when color telly was just being invented as well it's always a bit of fun to see that let's hope that they do manage to fix the problem quickly because we all enjoy
Seeing the graphics come up, the split of all the marks from all the judges, that's tremendously helpful from everyone's point of view.
It's really hard to use the flip cards nowadays because they blinker the judges.
So in between each of the judges there is a screen and you can't look across.
That also means that the judges closest to the recorder's table won't be able to see anything that the judges put up.
And there's three of them over there and there's four on the far side where the three meter springboards are.
Well, it's thrown the judging committee and the panel into a bit of turmoil.
And they're all now holding up the cards on the main table, holding up the cards for the judges to say, look, this is what we've got to go to.
We've got to go to the old paper system.
So electronics at the moment look to be out the window.
This is not good for Celine Van Duyn, incidentally.
It's OK if you're not up there on the steps or up there on the board.
You can take a little bit of a pause.
But if you're already up there, then this is a very twitchy moment.
And if you haven't got your competition underway either as well, then this is going to take a little bit of mental toughness to get through this period.
And it's the first round as well.
And the divers don't get settled until the first dive's over when they get wet.
Well, we had already got confirmation of that mark from Anjanami.
There it is again, 19.60.
So unfortunately, no reprieve for her.
She would just be very grateful that nothing else went wrong with that dive, because once that foot slipped away, she could have been in real trouble.
So time at last for Celine Van Doen.
That back twister that I described at 3.2.
She's got three dives that go into the three, so not a bad dive list from the 23-year-old Dutch woman.
And well, considering the weight, that was a pretty good effort.
Yeah, very good effort.
I did think she was going to ride over on the end, but she didn't.
She controlled the entry.
Here's the jump.
That was good.
Only a little bit away from the platform.
One and a half twist.
Now that's the hard bit pulling forwards into the pike.
Just a small wobble there.
The splash has been thrown up because her hand's not flat enough on the water, but technically a good dive.
in the prelims.
She only went 50 points.
This is far better.
Yes, 65-60.
Great opener.
And not the only person that had to wait.
Krasnozhlyuk of Ukraine would have been halfway up the steps waiting to go.
In with two and a half somersaults then for her.
That's a very good synchro record and has done well with Tatsenko in the past.
But on an individual basis, still looking for that first big result, just outside the medals last time around in fifth position.
But she has a little problem with flattening the feet off.
She did it in the prelims as well, but the dive overall is still good.
Yeah, in the prelims she was close.
This isn't close.
She didn't need to flatten her feet.
I think it's more of a habit now.
That was a really good take off.
Just need to keep those toes pointed.
She would have been all right.
Good entry, though.
So there's only maybe 10 centimeters of splash.
It's going to be a good score.
It is a good score.
63.
Coach Olga Ivanenko with a bit of advice.
And listen to this reception from the home crowd for the home athlete.
Georgia Ward diving in her home pool.
This is where she trains, along with Tom Daley and Coach Jane Figueredo.
already has a bronze medal from this European Championships in the team event with Mattie Lee and has a massive dive list.
She starts with the back twister.
It's okay, it's okay.
In terms of degree of difficulty, Chris, she has got a dive list that can rival anyone.
Yes, there's three divers doing back three and a halfs.
George is one of them.
Well, this is better than the prelims.
It went really over in the prelims.
This is just slightly over.
But technically strong.
I wonder if she'll be strong enough eventually to do two and a half twists.
She's a great diver.
She's already proved that.
Showed good resilience this morning to come back from a bad start.
But that's a good start.
Yeah, it's better than the prelims.
64 marks.
Georgia Ward in good shape.
28 years of age alongside Prokopchuk, the most experienced athlete in this field.
She's won this title before, she's not going to win it again with dives like that I'm afraid, a poor forward three and a half somersault opener.
She finished really high, but there's the problem, she's also jumped forward so
Although she's come out late from the pike.
Pike here is good but she is trapping forward.
Hard to stop the rotation and she reaches for the wrong part of the water.
Needed to reach more forward towards the one metre boards on the far side.
Just 45 marks from Batki and in this sort of company you can't afford those errors.
I talked about the fact that there are going to be misses and it's by how much you miss but
45 is probably too much.
She's going to have to rely on other athletes missing dives as well.
So forward three and a half somersaults now.
Same dive from Petrikova of Russia, the 19-year-old coached by her synchro partner's mother, Timoshenina, who saw her daughter miss out in the prelims.
So this is Russia's hope.
It's so-so.
It's not a bad entry, but it was very low.
So strong takeoff.
That was good.
Not traveling forward.
Just lining up in front of the face, going through the water.
So you see, just at the last minute, the feet kick.
She rolls under the water, brings some of it back.
A good jump at the start.
This will be a decent mark.
It's a good opener from Pechikova and she has the lead by just a third of a point from Eli Kalanji of France.
Two Germans to come next and always the same in each rotation of these five rounds.
Maria Corgio already has a gold from the synchro on the 10 meter.
And it's a solid start from her.
Nice entry.
Good forward three and a half.
Yeah, she did something funny with the feet though, going through the water.
Good jump, spinning fast.
Just the feet relaxing right here, which the judges will pick up.
As she rolls, her feet flatten.
It's a shame she'll lose five, six points for that.
But another diver makes it into the 60-point zone.
Good job at the moment in fifth position.
The German pair doing very well today to get through in third and fourth.
But for Christina Vass, and this is uncharted territory, the student from Berlin doesn't have any senior medals yet in the European Championships.
Could today be the day?
In with three and a half somersaults.
This is a big dive.
It was the second highest scoring dive.
No, it's not going to be far away again.
That's a great start from Rassen.
Yeah, 75 points.
I think the one in the prelims, though, the body was just a little tighter.
Springy jump.
Yeah, just there that.
Small mistake.
Everything else, though.
Good tuck.
Squeezing tight.
Spinning fast.
Finishing high.
And it's good.
It's safe as well.
Not too far or too close.
75.
Exactly the same score.
It is the final and the judges have gone with it.
Brilliant diving from Arsene and she opens once again with a 75 pointer to take the lead.
Two divers to come in round one.
Lulia Prokopchuk, the defending champion, looking to add a fifth 10 meter European Championship gold to her CV.
Forward three and a half then in the pike position at 3.0 for Lulia.
It's a much better start than the prelims.
Yeah, the prelims, she only got sixes.
Different pike.
She holds right down the bottom of her legs and has that gap going around.
But she got the tearing rip sound.
There's still a beautiful pike, though.
And look at that little movement.
So she'll get much higher than sixes.
75-2-0 leads for Germany and Christina Assen.
And just underneath that at 72 for a lower degree of difficulty.
That's a fine opener from Prokopchuk.
And once again, the decibel level goes up here in the London Aquatics Centre.
Tonya Couch, the 26-year-old from Plymouth, coached by Andy Banks to open her account in this final.
Same dive that we've just seen from Prokopchuk.
So a little bit of pressure on Couch here.
And that's the way to respond.
Maybe not quite as good on the entry as Prokopchuk, but that will certainly get her off to a great start.
Tonya had a better start, though.
This jumps up in the air, and the pike is better.
The face is across the top of the legs.
Yes, it had a little bit more splash.
But technically, I think this was superior.
Slightly flat feet and then pointed again, coming out.
But the splash, that's what the judges might mark her down for.
Oh, wow.
Well, that was really unfair.
That is a tough call for Tonya Couch.
61-50.
She's not happy.
And that is not the start that she was looking for.
Well, we told you it would be interesting.
It's the youngster, 17-year-old Christina Watson, that leads at the moment.
We'll take the break there.
Round two of the women's 10-meter final on day five here at the European Diving Championships on Eurosport.
Armstand back to somersaults with a half twist for Eli Kalonji of France.
Nicely done.
She started this competition on fire.
Yeah, in fourth place, qualified in 12.
That's a half twist first and then into the pike.
A bit wobbly though with a loose back going through the water.
Good at this point.
Arms lining up in front.
Hardly any splash.
But doesn't really squeeze the ears with the arms and lock the body out.
Well degree of difficulty of just 2.7 is always going to be tough to get yourself into the 60s but solid diving from her.
Now Laura Marino has already made her mistake.
A big miss in round one.
That's out of the way.
She now needs four rounds of world-class diving if she wants a shot at the medal.
Forward three and a half somersaults in the pike position then in round two for Marino.
That's better.
Just a little loose on the entry.
Again, the technique is good.
What we're looking for is upright and then the first part of the somersault to move up and then drop.
So there she gets it.
Pike is near perfect, the face very clushing.
Pulling in hard.
Second and third somersault faster than the first because the pike's tighter.
63 marks for Marinot.
May
Enable her to advance a position or two.
And as Chris Snowd said, 70s is where you need to be this evening if you want to get in amongst the medals and take that gold.
Now, Anjarami, the Lithuanian, a really scary start for her.
She got away with it.
So four, three and a half somersaults in round two.
Oh my goodness me, and it's going from bad to worse, I'm afraid, for the Lithuanian.
That is a poor dive and it's a painful one.
Yeah, so on the inwards she caught it on the face.
Now a whole of her back completely slaps.
So she misses her spot.
This is good.
Lovely tuck position.
And misses it.
Doesn't see the triple.
Divers feel the triple come around, then they look at the water, and then they reach for it.
And she just stayed in the tuck.
Still smiling.
Unbelievable.
And hasn't made it to 30 points yet.
Well, let's just hope, for her sake, that things improve.
Celine van Doornen for the Netherlands.
2.8 for this next round.
Inward two and a half somersaults then.
This is the dive that Kalonjic really nailed first up in this final for France.
What can Celine do?
Well, very graceful through the air.
It looked, if anything, a little easy for her.
That's because she did all the right movements.
The throw was at the right time.
You have to coordinate the throw with the jump.
Pulls it straight away.
So she was into the pike as tight as you can be right at the beginning.
Some of the divers take half a rotation to get in there.
A little splashy on the entry.
58.80.
Keeps Celine Vander and score ticking along nicely.
That's nice lick for Ukraine.
The 20 year old will be performing a forward three and a half somersaults in the pike position at three point.
Oh, this is actually her highest degree of difficulty.
It was a best dive in the prelims.
Just waiting for that whistle confirmation that she's good to go and she's got it.
So in her own time.
No, and that's washed over again.
So, well, the pressure coming to bear, that little bit of additional adrenaline, and it can make a huge difference to the dives.
Sometimes when you tighten up in a competition, things just don't flow.
She hit the end of the diving board, and she didn't throw in time, so the momentum of the jog down the pole has taken her out, and then she misses her spot.
Pike is OK.
It's been quite a few misses now.
52.50 Not far off, but not quite there.
Opportunities opening up, left, right and centre here.
Can Georgia Ward take her chance?
She's got the dive list, that high degree of difficulty to do it.
Back three and a half somersaults in the tuck position at 3.3, the toughest dive in the competition.
Oh, well done, Georgia.
What a dive.
I knew that was coming.
The last two attempts, she has gone short.
And I'm sure her coach has said, kick your feet up.
Don't kick them back towards the ball.
She did that.
Gets the reach back.
And with 3.3, this is going to be a phenomenal score.
At the moment, the highest score has been 75 in the prelims.
Can she go 80?
That response from the crowd, massive, and she has done.
80.85 puts Georgia Ward in the hunt for gold.
Noemi Bakke for Italy.
Three-time silver medalist in this event in 10-14, but she also won it back in 2011.
So the platform has been kind.
to the Italian.
In with three and a half somersaults then round two to make up for that miss in round one.
Oh, she really kicked hard for that and put everything into the entry.
There was a booming sound as she goes through the water.
And the tuck is really tight as well.
Here, squeezing, chin very close to the knees, pops out of it, flat hand entry, and the boom goes around the whole of the poolside.
Brilliant diving from Batki.
Now we're cooking.
Another 80.
Look at that.
And Batki goes to 125 for second place behind Georgia Ward.
And that is the way to send the message out to the rest of this field.
Katerina Petrikova then.
Next for Russia.
In with three and a half somersaults for her at 3.2.
She has got a tough dive list as well.
Everything in the threes.
And she does the 3.3 in the next round.
Oh, it's great diving, and this competition, Chris, has come alive.
These are world-class dives.
As we said in the earlier competitions, though, the standard is high.
It's Olympic here.
Everyone's been preparing very hard since last September, and you can see it.
Gets the little roll on the entry, a bit of splash, but still a good dive.
Brilliant.
70.40 for Pechikova.
And this one, this competition is warming up nicely.
Maria Kojo then.
Already has that gold medal with Maipan in the 10 meter synchro competition, but that was a little unexpected.
And in the end, the medal came due to some misses by other teams, but she'll take it.
Sports soldier by trade, but currently studying as a law and psychology student.
And she's going to need all of that experience to put into this arm stand.
Back twister.
Well done.
Another rip entry.
3.2 degree of difficulty.
She gets a push off her arms before going into the one and a half twist.
That's good there.
Now pulls forward, looks at the water, lines up just in time.
What a dive.
And that looked fabulous on that last slo-mo.
And that's a fabulous score.
76.80 takes it to 1.3980.
5.05 off of the pace set at the moment by the Brit, Georgia Ward.
Kristina Wasson will always follow Kojo in every round.
Lovely start from the 17-year-old.
Another 75 would do nicely.
No, and it's not going to happen.
There's the mistake from Wasson then.
Washes it over.
Exactly the same as the prelim.
She hangs onto the pipe too long.
The feet go up to the 10 meter and over onto her stomach.
needs to be out now she's still in the pike and she finished something like five and a half meters there you can see the five meter board as she's coming out and just the feet have gone to the wrong place tough break for Wassen 30.45 dumps her down to ninth place with two still to come well Liliya Prokocuk in second position behind Wassen
with her 70 pointer in the first round.
Much better start than she made in the prelims.
In with three and a half in the tuck position now.
High degree of difficulty.
Looking for the big score.
And we get an enormous score.
That's a fabulous dive.
She finished so high on it.
This is a hard dive.
And she had so much time at the end.
Double there.
Now she finished above the five meter.
We've already had 280 dives.
This is on the same par as Georgia Ward.
Astonishing stuff in round two.
It's another 80.
81-60 puts Prakopchuk in the lead.
So she will move ahead of Georgia Ward by 8.75 points.
Talk about pressure for Tonya Couch.
blew everyone away for most of the prelim.
Had an error at the end, which led a few athletes get closer to her, but came into this competition as the marginal favorite and has to produce some magic here.
Arm stand back twister then.
Antonio Couch is in business.
Well, we've had some, this is one of the best rounds I've seen at Europeans for a long, long time.
Nails it.
So at the moment the highest score is 81.6.
Well, her feet were better than the prelims, so this is going to be massive.
Yeah, it's going to be 80.
Oh, it's 86.4.
Back into second position at 147.90 and just five points down on Lulia Prokopciuk.
What a competition.
A simple dive for Alea Kalanji.
You'll see it on the replay, but unfortunately she has problems with the reverse dive family and has to stick to that.
A very simple dive at 1.9.
She's done it beautifully again.
Yeah, she has, but because of that low degree of difficulty or come up as a very low score, somewhere around 40 points, she would have gone even higher with the score if she hadn't had that drift over at the end.
39.90 for Kalanji.
And that's the dive that is always going to cause us some problems until she builds some high degree of difficulty in.
Well, Laura Moreno must be wondering what an earth is going on in this competition because it's all happening around her.
Has not found a good divers yet.
The French woman who finished in second place in 2015 in Rostock.
She would dearly love to come to the party in round three with this back two and a half somersaults.
Oh, why not?
Why not?
Another brilliant entry.
Well, maybe this is going to be the round where she starts to pick up.
Good jump.
Looking with her head.
You can see her head moving.
Here, she looks at the end of the board, sees it, looks at the water, sees it, reaches back and sees it and disappears.
Yes, what a lovely way of describing the process that the diver is going through, Chris.
Brilliant.
And that's a good score.
73.95 for Laura Marino.
A little collision with the camera operator, but she's happy.
Wouldn't have been smiling if she'd got a 40, I can tell you.
Now, Genevieve and Jeremy, keep your fingers crossed.
Friday the 13th is a day that at the moment she would prefer to forget.
No, it's still not happening, I'm afraid, for Genevieve.
Well, for the first three quarters of the dive, it's fine.
Good jump.
Spot's well on the first somersault, but she doesn't pick up the second spot.
Here it's good.
But right here, she's looking in the wrong place.
She should have seen the water and then pushed her feet out.
She leaves it too late.
It's gone over.
Well, the smile once again.
But it's looking a little tired now.
33.35, still only managing to get to 62 marks after three rounds of diving.
Celine Vando and then forward three and a half somersaults in the pike position at 3.0.
Diving well, but the class around here from some of the big names at the moment eclipsing anything that she's managed to do.
So round three needs to be big for the Dutch woman.
It's a good dive.
A little bit of a depth charge going up after the entry, but she'll take that.
Yeah, this is correct.
She jumps up.
The one in prelim jumped forward.
But as she's coming out, the whole of the middle of her body is loose.
She's not holding the stomach tight.
The back goes loose.
And the water then hits you, and your body concertinas.
And that's why this flash has come up.
I'm still waiting for that mark.
And 58.50.
If that's as bad as it gets, then it's not going to be too bad for Celine Van doing.
But in this kind of company at the moment, it isn't good enough.
That's Nuzlic then next.
9th position after two rounds.
Forward twister, so two and a half somersaults then with a single twist.
Let's see where she puts the twist in to this particular dive.
So the twist straight away then pulls into the somersaults and a nice entry.
Yeah, just a small jump forward.
Yeah, as she landed on the board, her body bent forward there and as she's throwing down rather than forwards.
Gets a good entry though.
Just a little bit sloppy on the start and just going into the pike.
Could have a little deeper pike.
Once again, coach Ivanenko comes across for a chap.
60.90.
That's Narslik giving a good account of herself.
Now Georgia Ward, you get the feeling actually that it was Georgia that really kicked this competition into life in round two.
Absolutely nailed her back three and a half.
Went into the lead and everybody found it difficult to live with her from there.
So arm stand back to somersaults with one and a half twists for Georgia Ward in a home pull.
Another good dive here.
And she is definitely in business.
Oh, superb.
That little separation of the legs as she came away from the platform, but got it all back together.
Yeah, it's so minor that it's not going to affect.
the judge's score.
The loose body going through the water will drop her down a little bit.
She went 67 points in the prelim.
This is just about the same dive.
Very good in the air.
Bit splashy going through the water, so it'll be a similar score.
67 points will keep her on track, and that's where she is.
67-2-0 for 212.05.
Ward moves back into the lead.
Noemi Bakke, then.
from a Hungarian diver that moved to Italy back in 2005, coached by Mami Bolyanaj, the 1992 Olympian from Barcelona.
Has been superb in this competition in previous years, but isn't happening for her at the moment.
Reverse two and a half then for Noemi.
Well, wonderful.
How high did she go off the platform there?
And always in control.
She didn't hold back.
She's standing there.
She thought about it.
She visualized it.
And then she jumped.
She was kicking out at seven and a half meters.
The double here, seven and a half meters kick.
She floats around for six meters.
There's the seven meter right next to her.
And then she reaches back.
What a dive.
Into the 70s.
And remember, that's a lower degree of difficulty at 2.8.
So that score is fabulous.
And Mum is happy.
Katerina Petrikova then in fifth position at the moment.
Sometimes in the shadow of her synchro partner, Timoshenina.
has a chance to shine here because Timoshenina failed to get through the prelims so back three and a half this is her toughest dive equal toughest dive in the competition oh and it's a nasty one so again another big miss and this time it's from the russian missed it in the previous only scored 40 something points on it the jump is good but it's spinning too slow she hangs on as long as possible and then goes over
It's not accelerating, it's just dropping like a stone, and barely time to come out.
She'll be lucky to get 40 on this one.
That was even worse than the prelim.
Yeah, it's just 37.95 then for Petrkova.
A real shame for her, and that's probably the medal challenge done for the Russian.
But never say never, anything can happen where platform diving is concerned.
And it did in the prelims.
A few big names missing out, a few big names nearly missing out.
Marie Courget then, the 27-year-old German.
Trains in Berlin coached by Jan Kretschmar.
And that's really nice.
But on a day she's a very tidy, very efficient diver and that's what she's bringing to this final.
She finished in 12th place last year, but she's got three bronze medals in this event from 11, 12 and 2013.
It was a good dive.
It's a lower degree of difficulty.
I was watching her toes as she passed the board and it was just about safe enough, any closer than she would have touched.
Solid score, 60.20 to reach the 200 mark.
after three rounds of five.
Slightly disconsolate look from Christina Arsene.
There she went from first to 11th.
And that's not going to keep anyone happy.
So Arsene armstand dive for her.
Armstand back to somersaults, one and a half twists.
And that gives her a degree of difficulty of 3.2.
So this is the kind of dive
if she gets the entry that she was getting in the prelims that could put her back in contention.
It's good, it's good, but it's not going to push her up too far on the leaderboard.
There's a better handstand this time in the prelim.
She didn't get to that completely straight position.
Now she is just twisting all the way down to the pole.
But it's an entry, it's going to score really well.
Technique isn't that brilliant off the platform, not enough jump and the twist took so long to get into.
70.40 then, takes her to 176.05, so she will improve her position from 11th to round about 9th.
Just a reminder, Georgia Ward leads for Great Britain on 212.05.
Prokopchuk and her compatriot Tonya Couch can get past her.
And with diving like this, the defence of her title is starting to look very, very good indeed.
That's a great dive on that back two and a half.
What a jump.
Spots.
Just collapses a little bit going through the water.
Here it's good.
Reaches back.
She needs only 58 points to go into the lead.
I guess she'll get that.
And the four-time European 10-meter champion moves back into top spot.
2.2175.
So that's a 9.7 advantage.
over Georgia Ward in second, 21.7 advantage over Maria Kujo in third.
And Tonya Kouch has got this tough position, the pressure keeps passing down.
Inward three and a half then for Tonya at 3.2.
And she will keep pace with that dive.
She needs 73 points to go and lead.
I'm not quite sure.
With that entry, she pulls her chin down on the end.
But that start is good.
Finishes high, but just lost it on the entry.
Need to have the confidence to keep stretching.
She pushes here, and you see the arms are out of line.
So the judges will mark her down for that.
So probably sub-70, but by how much?
Well, just under five points.
So Tonya Couch does move into second at 2.1350, just ahead of Georgia Ward, but it's the defending champion Prokopchuk that leads.
Back just in time for another rip entry, this time from Laura Mourinho, the French number one, after that arm stand, back two somersaults and one and a half twists.
Another lovely entry, using the bend knee to flick off.
A lot of the ladies are just leaning off.
That's why I like that technique.
Gets a little bit of extra rotation and a fast twist.
But it's the entry, little splash, that's given her the 73 points.
OK, moves to 260.15 after that 73.60.
So a couple of good rounds there from Laura Marino, and she's kind of back in business.
but needs to keep it at the highest possible level if she's going to be in with a shout of a place on the podium.
Now, come on, Genevieve.
17-year-old from Lithuania.
Reverse two-and-a-half somersaults.
Needs an entry.
Needs to get some confidence back.
And it's just not going to happen for her this evening.
And you sometimes get competitions like this, Chris.
It doesn't matter what you do, it doesn't work.
Sometimes when you've got experience, if you're spinning at a different rate in the competition, you know to make adjustments and that's what's happened here.
She's jumped a little higher than normal, she's spinning faster than normal, but she's done the same kick out that she would do in practice and that is why she's gone over.
The extra adrenaline she hasn't taken into account.
Still a high school student back in the USA but retained her Lithuanian passport when she moved there.
at two years of age and has to put this one down to experience, I'm afraid, this evening.
Celine Van Leeuwen has dived very well and seventh the best that she can manage at the moment.
This then her joint toughest dive, arm stand back to somersaults with one and a half twists.
So like her back twister in the first round, it's worth 3.2.
in terms of degree of difficulty.
Is this the dive that puts her back in business?
Not quite, I'm afraid.
Again, just going over on the end and judges will certainly deduct for that.
Not only did she lean, but she had the bent knee flick, which just gave her a little too much rotation.
When she pikes down, she couldn't stop it, digs the head in as well.
That actually accelerated those legs going over.
That would be a miss for her.
52.80.
It is a miss.
Van Doorn will not be able to recover from that.
So that's her medal challenge done.
Hannah Krasnowska then for Ukraine.
Again, dive very solidly, but in this kind of company, eighth position, the best that she can manage at the moment.
Unlikely to match her fifth place from 2015, which was a brilliant performance.
No it's very strange start to that back two and a half.
Yeah she keeps her knees bent so right here her legs are bent and then she finally straightens up those legs for the second part of the dive but that's an untidy pipe there.
Here doesn't spot the water that looks to me more like a guess rather than using your eyes to see where to come around where to come out and she's gone right over.
2.19.90 that
rolling score and that's a miss at 43.50.
Lauren Marino leads for France then on 2.61.5.
Georgia Ward will be looking to go past her and by some distance with this fourth round dive.
Forward three and a half somersaults in the pike position then her lowest degree of difficulty.
This needs to be perfect.
Oh and again just washes over at the end.
Oh she'll be frustrated with that
Oh, that's a real shame.
She only needed 48 points to go in the lead.
Well, she's got such a good take-off here.
Pulls him well there.
Needed to be out already.
Yeah.
Now, she's nailed that entry.
She'll get an extra 15 points.
Oh, she had.
Yeah, coach Figueredo watching on, and 57 gives her the lead at 269.05, but it's not the kind of advancement that she was looking for.
If that is Georgia Ward's miss, then OK, she'll probably take that one.
Big dive to come in the final round for her.
For Noemi Bakke, so far, this has not been her European championships.
Fifth position at the moment, so outside the medals, but still has the degree of difficulty to force a way onto the podium.
She needs 70 points to catch Georgia Ward.
No and that just was one of those classic arm stand dives where the diver just falls straight off the platform and into the water.
Yeah she needs to go back in the gym to work on this to get the timing.
She just hasn't got the timing and that's why it looks so awkward.
That's a miss for her.
You can see how low she finishes to the water.
Not a great dive to watch, not a great score to get.
54-4-0, back is challenged, falters again.
Ekaterina Petrikova, one miss, too many.
And she's down in 10th position, but in this kind of competition and in this kind of company, one miss is too many.
Slightly different arm stand position here.
Facing the pull with her back for this two somersaults single twist at 3.1.
Unusual dive this.
Both she and Timoshenina have the same technique for the push-off and it's really effective.
Yeah, the hips go first and then the feet flick.
So there's the hips and then the flick, then the single twist and look at the water.
Yeah, it's a good technique.
Maybe just bending the arms a little too much.
You only have to relax your arms rather than bend them right down.
It's actually quite a complicated dive.
And that's a good score.
68-20 takes it to 2.4405, so partial recovery once again from Petrkova.
Now, Chris, you think that Maria Cujo could be the danger.
Back two and a half somersaults from her in the pike position.
Yeah, she only needs 69 points to take the lead.
And she went, she actually missed this dive in the prelims.
Only got 56.
She's got to remember to come out in time, not let the dive go over.
Oh, it's gone over again.
Almost carbon copy of the prelims.
Yeah, you should be able to make an adjustment in the prelims.
If you're going to go short, you have the same sort of pressure because you're wanting to make the top 12.
You need to remember to come out early.
Looks at the water too late.
It's bypassed her and out too late.
So right over.
42.05 and that miss, I'm afraid.
is going to put the lid on Kujo's challenge and less others miss around her.
For Vasan, same situation as Kujo except her miss occurred on the last dive.
So Vasan trying to repair the damage with this forward three and a half somersaults in the pike position.
Oh, that's more like the entries we saw from her in the prelims.
It's amazing that she could get down with no splash, even with the dive going over.
So it's going to score well.
Yeah, she attacks the end of the diving board.
Pulling in well here.
Again, the technique of holding down on the lower part of the legs rather than around the back of the knees.
It doesn't matter if you get an entry like that.
Good awareness, good scoop under the water.
to save that dive and that's a good score.
67.50 puts Varsan temporarily up to fifth position with two divers still to come in this round.
Arm stand back, three somersaults in the tuck position for Lulia Prokopchuk for the joint highest degree of difficulty in the competition at 3.3.
This is the big dive for her, Chris.
If she gets this right, gold and defensive title is on.
It's only a 75.9 in the prelim.
She only needs 48 points to go ahead of Georgia.
Oh, it's beautiful from Prokopchuk.
She has not missed a beat this evening.
Well, if she gets eight, which it's worth, it's going to be 75 again.
Strong kick out.
Oh, this is even better than the prelims.
Look, sharp kick, reaches back, tightens her body, quick save under the water, stops the feet kicking over.
That's the way to go through.
She's always known what she's doing.
She saw that triple somersault from about four meters up.
Chris Snowd loved it, but more importantly, the judges loved it.
84.15 takes her over 300.
305.90 leads.
She's just put 36 points between her and George Ward in second place, and she's done it again.
She's passed all the pressure down the line to the 26-year-old Brit, Tonya Couch.
Back, twister then for Tonya at 3.2, just to stay in touch.
Oh, what a response from Tonya Couch.
Yeah, the pressure hasn't affected her at all.
They're still making her sharp.
She won't be able to catch Lida 92 points ahead, but that's going to still give her a chance.
If she misses, Tonya and even Georgia will have a chance on that final round.
Great fourth dive.
Couch looking to stay within touching distance, and she does.
72 marks takes her to 285.50.
That means she's just over 20 points behind Lulia Prokopciuk with one round of diving in this 10-meter final to go.
So Prokopciuk, the defending champion, leads, and she's got a handy cushion ahead of Couch and Ward, the two Brits in second and third.
One round then, left to come.
And one round of real drama, I'm sure, in store for us here in London.
Well, we teed this competition up at the start of the evening as potential drama, and it's exactly what we've got.
Last round of dives, then, in the women's 10-meter final at this 2016 European Championships.
Eli Kalonji, 18-year-old from
Paris has given a really good account of herself.
This to sign off their no medal tonight for a light, but it's a really good performance.
And she's been solid tonight.
She really has.
She has a unique sound to her entries.
It's not even quite a tearing sound.
It's just strange noise.
It's more of a thud, isn't it?
Yeah, but it's mesmerizing.
So clearly she's not as experienced as the other divers, but she looks quite poetic with her dives anyway.
And then you get this really strange, solid sound on the entry.
I do like that.
Moves to 2, 7, 9, 3, 0 for Kalonji.
And that's really good work from the 18-year-old.
Great experience.
Compatriot Laura Marino has already experienced a silver medal at these championships back in 2015.
But for her today, it just hasn't quite happened.
So back and forth at the moment, meaning this back two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists has to be the best that she can make it.
If she can get up into the high 70s, 80s, maybe there's a chance.
Oh no, just very short.
Yeah, when she was on the platform, the arms didn't swing up over her head.
She looked very rigid here.
then going forward into the plaque after the twist it's just too low to the water yeah very slow on the somersault she tried to stay into the plaque as long as she could but couldn't get around to the vertical position she was nine points behind georgia who was in third place at the end of round four and after her full
Five rounds of diving.
She's only eight points ahead of Prakopchuk, who's had four rounds.
So that puts it into context.
It's unlikely to be a medal for Marino this evening.
Genevieve Green-Anjirame, then, of Lithuania, the 17-year-old, still smiling.
The crowd have responded really well to her.
She's had a torrid time tonight.
Started off in the first round poorly.
That's knocked her confidence and just wants an entry in this final dive.
And she's got it at last.
Well done to Genevieve Anjarami.
Yeah, the highest score she's had at this point was 43.
She's got a 33, a 19, and an 8.
But finally, this is a dive that is worthy of the European Championship.
Good jump, lovely pike there.
Locks out.
It's a shame it's a low degree of difficulty, but they'll go more than 43 points.
What they can't take away from her is the fact that she's finished 12th in a European Championship.
And that's something certainly to brag about.
So Anjarami signs off with a good one.
Celine Van Doorn will want to be doing the same.
Best finish that she's had in this competition was last year and that was a ninth place.
So a good dive here and she could improve on that.
Qualified in ninth.
She came ninth last year and she's in ninth at the moment.
Back two and a half then for Celine.
Oh, it's a nice finish but she keeps throwing up that plume of splash when she goes through the water.
Yeah, that's not because of the takeoff.
This is good.
The pike is good.
But she just doesn't reach back enough with her hands.
It's almost like her shoulders are too tight and it's an effort to get the arms back there.
Needs to be reaching back there.
Doesn't do that.
The arms are in front of the ears and the body just collapses a little bit.
56.55 then for Van Doorn.
That little clunk you heard on the microphone then, that is my co-commentator Chris Snow basically demonstrating everything he talks about.
It's an animated commentary box, I can tell you.
I'm like the Italians.
Oh, they've had a good week, the Italians, and it might still get better as well with Delape and Cagnotto to go in the three-meter synchro later this week.
Now back to this competition.
Krasnozlic to sign off for Ukraine.
She's had a solid night this evening.
No, bad take-off.
How did she find that entry?
Where did that come from?
Feels like there's oil on the end of the diving board and she just slipped off.
She didn't get any jump, just slides there.
Kicks good though.
And the entry's fine as well.
Well, if she can get that start better, the judges won't be marking her down.
That'll be a 70-pointer.
The entry, though, will get still some good scores.
64-4-0 for Hanna Krasnozlic to finish off and acknowledges the applause from the crowd although some of that applause very definitely directed towards this young woman.
Georgia Ward then another big moment for her.
Already had one big moment in the team competition diving for that bronze medal and this is a chance of another medal right here.
Inward three and a half somersaults in the tuck position at 3.2 to post a score for a medal.
Oh no, and it's a miss, I'm afraid, from Ward.
I'll tell you what though, she might still go ahead of Marino.
A good tuck, just a little slow, hesitating coming out for that to kick over.
Everything's good at this point, but out too late, and kicks.
And 325.05.
She does get past Laura Murano of France to lead for the moment.
325 is still a good score.
Badkeet with her final dive.
She has not performed well this evening, but unbelievably, just down in fifth position, is there something for her?
still to be had from this competition.
3.2, the degree of difficulty for this back twister.
If she hits it, she can score big.
No.
And that's not going to do it.
No, she needed 74 points to go ahead of Georgia Wall to have any chance of a medal.
Doesn't get the jump, leans back, and very short.
Feet apart.
wobbling around.
That's a poor last eye for her.
You've got to get that jump up off the tower.
She just hasn't had that, has she?
She hasn't had that snap this evening.
3-0-8, 4-0, so third position at the moment.
Georgia Ward of Great Britain still leads on 325.05, with three or four challenges still in the mix.
And Constellation peck on the cheek there from Mum for Noemi Bakki.
Katerina Petrikova at sixth position.
Well, can she at least record a score to ask some questions here?
She would have to go nines to go ahead of Georgia Ward to get 81 points.
Oh, wow.
And is that back twister worth nines, Chris, on finals night?
It's not worth nines.
Maybe an eight.
The jump's good, very fast twist.
There's just too much splash to go any higher than an 8.
Technically good, but yeah, she doesn't get the final lockout.
Maybe 70s.
Well, judges agree with you.
Just the 1.8 in there, 7.5 for 72, 3.1605.
So Petrkova finishes up behind Georgia Ward.
And Ward moving ever closer to a medal.
Couriot, that one miss in the last round has basically cost her everything.
Back twister then, two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists in the pike position at 3.2, but she too would have to go near to the maximum.
Yeah, she would need nine and maybe one nine and a half to get to 3.25, which is what Georgia Ward's on.
No, doesn't get the jump, finishes below the board on that first one and a half twist.
Doesn't finish extending the legs on the jump, opening the pike, and ducks her head down on the entry.
And Ward has seen another challenger for a medal off.
And Courjou, who was one of the danger women in this draw, is below 300, and that's below par, way below par for her.
So Maria Curio signs off.
Three more to come.
And well, Wassen has got to find a phenomenal score.
And mathematically, it may not even be possible.
Well, nines, Chris Snow is saying.
Nines for Wassen if she wants to get close to Georgia Ward's score for a bronze medal.
It's a good dive.
It's a really good effort.
But again, it's not going to be enough.
No, that little movement on the end will keep it down to seven halves, maybe an eight again.
Just too much movement over.
She's watching on the replay, just bent legs a little bit, and I think she's gone over too far.
Well, you can hear those scores in the background.
You can multiply that against the 3.2, and what it means is that Georgia Ward
is going to take a medal away from this European Championship final.
The colour will be decided by the next two divers.
So Vasen signs off with 310 scored and Prokopchuk takes a big deep breath.
From her point of view, this back twister is all about shutting the door on the rest.
So to move into top spot, she doesn't have to do too much.
She just has to perform a fifth dive quite beautifully, and that's probably gold.
I tell you what, I reckon she's going to break the European record.
It's 373.3 that she set in 2013.
That is a really good call, Chris, and she thoroughly deserves it.
That's five rounds of cracking diving from Prokopchuk.
She's going to smash the record.
Certainly she's going to get more than 68 points.
And Prokopchuk looks like she's defended her title to make it five goals and a new European record at 385.90.
Prokopchuk reigning supreme here in this pool.
Now, that would have got her a bronze medal at the Olympic Games.
Well, that's what everybody's looking for against the rest of the world in Rio.
And Prokopchuk will go there in great form.
Couch then still diving for a medal.
And that'll do it.
Brilliant dive from Tonya Couch, and the celebration under the water tells you all you need to know.
She's done it.
She's got her medal at last.
And what a way to do it.
She's got tens on this dive before.
Not quite a ten because just a little splashy.
But look how high she finishes.
She just continues to float down from seven meters.
This is her favorite dive.
That's why she's got it here in round number five.
It's a reliable one.
We've promised you a good one to start the evening.
We've got a new European record.
We've got two medals for Great Britain.
Tonya Couch, at the expense of her compatriot, Georgia Ward, claims the silver.
But Georgia Ward will be delighted with her second medal at this Europeans.
But hats off to Lulia Prokopchuk.
That new record of 385.90 is right up there with the rest of the world.
and it's the defense of her title to make it five 10 meter gold medals for her and for Ukraine.
Brilliant performance, Prokopchuk is the champion.